<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aptitude on Tech Notebook</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/aptitude/</link><description>Recent content in Aptitude on Tech Notebook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 17:45:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/aptitude/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apt &amp; Aptitude: Useful Commands</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/apt-aptitude-les-commandes-utiles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 11:24:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/apt-aptitude-les-commandes-utiles/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Being an Ubuntu/Debian user (yes, I use and advocate both), I have fallen in love with the Advanced Packaging Tool, also known as apt. Before Ubuntu, I played in the world of RPM hell, with distros such as Red Hat itself, Mandrake (as it was called back then), and even SuSE. I would find some piece of software, try to install it, only to find that it would choke, saying that it relied on some certain dependencies. I would install the dependencies, only to find conflicting versions with newer software. Hell indeed. So when I discovered the Debian way of installing software, I wondered why no one had mentioned it to me before. It was heaven. This is the way to software, I thought.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advanced Usage of Debian Packages</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Utilisation_avanc%C3%A9e_des_packages_Debian/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 21:54:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Utilisation_avanc%C3%A9e_des_packages_Debian/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Quite possibly the most distinguishing feature of Debian-based Linux distributions (such as Ubuntu, Mepis, Knoppix, etc) is their package system – APT. Also known as the Advanced Package Tool, APT was first introduced in Debian 2.1 in 1999. APT is not so much a specific program as it is a collection of separate, related packages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With APT, Linux gained the ability to install and manage software packages in a much simpler and more efficient way than was previously possible. Before its introduction, most software had to be installed either by manually compiling the source code, or using individual packages with no automatic dependency handling (such as RPM files). This could mean hours of &amp;ldquo;dependency hell&amp;rdquo; even to install a fairly trivial program.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>