<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GitHub on Tech Notebook</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in GitHub on Tech Notebook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 18:51:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to XHTML</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Introduction_au_XHTML/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 07:38:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Introduction_au_XHTML/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>XHTML is a markup language used for writing World Wide Web pages. Originally designed as the successor to HTML, XHTML is based on the syntax defined by XML, which is more recent and simpler than the syntax defined by SGML on which HTML is based.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like many XML-based languages, XHTML begins with the letter X, which represents the word &amp;ldquo;extensible&amp;rdquo;. Thus, the first document officially describing XHTML is called &amp;ldquo;XHTML™ 1.0 The Extensible HyperText Markup Language&amp;rdquo;. However, the abbreviation XHTML is a trademark of the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) and is the only one used in the specifications that followed version 1.0.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction to Shell Scripting</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Introduction_au_Script_Shell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 11:53:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Introduction_au_Script_Shell/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Bourne-again shell is the free command interpreter of the GNU project. Its name is a play on words (Bourne again / born again) referring to the historic Unix shell, the Bourne shell. Based on the latter, it brings many improvements, notably from the Korn shell and the C shell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The original author is Brian Fox of the Free Software Foundation, later succeeded by Chet Ramey. The original Bourne shell was written by Steve Bourne.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction to C</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Introduction_au_C/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 12:50:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Introduction_au_C/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The history of the C language is intimately linked to that of the UNIX operating system. In 1965, Ken Thompson, from Bell Labs, developed an operating system that he called MULTICS (Multiplexed Information and Computing System) in order to run a game he had created, which gave birth in 1970 to the UNICS operating system (Uniplexed Information and Computing System), quickly renamed UNIX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the time, assembly language was the only language that allowed the development of an operating system. Ken Thompson then developed a higher-level language, the B language (whose name comes from BCPL, a subset of the CPL language, itself derived from Algol, a language that was popular at the time), to facilitate the writing of operating systems. It was a weakly typed language (an untyped language, as opposed to a typed language, is a language that manipulates objects in their binary form, without any notion of type (character, integer, real, etc.)) and too dependent on the PDP-7 (the machine on which UNIX was developed) to allow UNIX to be ported to other machines. So Denis Ritchie (who was, along with Ken Thompson, one of the creators of UNIX) and Brian Kernighan improved the B language to give birth to the C language. In 1973, UNIX was rewritten entirely in C. For 5 years, the C language was limited to internal use at Bell until the day Brian Kernighan and Denis Ritchie published a first definition of the language in a book entitled &amp;ldquo;The C Programming Language&amp;rdquo;. This was the beginning of a revolution in the world of computing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>