<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Anti-Spam on Tech Notebook</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/anti-spam/</link><description>Recent content in Anti-Spam on Tech Notebook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 17:45:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/anti-spam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FuzzyOcr Plugin: Image Spam Detection (OCR Detection)</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/FuzzyOcr_Plugin_:_D%C3%A9tection_des_spams_image_%28OCR_Detection%29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 10:36:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/FuzzyOcr_Plugin_:_D%C3%A9tection_des_spams_image_%28OCR_Detection%29/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>The most widely used anti-spam tool in the open-source world is SpamAssassin. Its operation is similar to that of the amavisd-new service. It collects results obtained from a collection of other tools and passes them to the amavisd-new service, which makes a decision about the message based on its total score.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a system perspective, implementing SpamAssassin is very simple. Just use the Debian/testing package, which is well maintained. This situation is particularly interesting because the collection of libraries and tools dependent on SpamAssassin is very large. The command:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SPF (Sender Policy Framework): Prevention of Email Address Forgery</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/SPF_%28Sender_Policy_Framework%29_:_Pr%C3%A9vention_de_la_contrefa%C3%A7on_d%27adresses_mails/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 22:59:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/SPF_%28Sender_Policy_Framework%29_:_Pr%C3%A9vention_de_la_contrefa%C3%A7on_d%27adresses_mails/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>SPF stands for Sender Policy Framework. SPF aims to be an anti-counterfeiting standard to prevent email address forgery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SPF was born in 2003. Its creator, Meng Weng Wong, took the best features of Reverse MX and DMP (Designated Mailer Protocol) to create SPF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SPF uses the return path (MAIL FROM) present in the message header, since all MTAs work with these fields. However, there is a new concept proposed by Microsoft: PRA, which stands for Purported Responsible Address. The PRA corresponds to the end-user address that an MUA (like Thunderbird) uses.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>