<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hiding on Tech Notebook</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/hiding/</link><description>Recent content in Hiding on Tech Notebook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 20:33:41 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/hiding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Banners: Hiding Application Banners (Service Banner Faking)</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Bani%C3%A8res_:_Cacher_les_bani%C3%A8res_de_ses_applications_%28Service_banner_faking%29/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2009 20:56:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Bani%C3%A8res_:_Cacher_les_bani%C3%A8res_de_ses_applications_%28Service_banner_faking%29/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>This is a quick howto on faking service banners. Service banners often contain a lot of useful information for malicious script-kiddies, like the (real) running software on the remote host and its version number. Knowing this, they can better target their exploits. This howto deals with changing this information. Keep in mind that this won&amp;rsquo;t make your system more secure against a known exploit when you run a vulnerable service, however it can provide some &amp;lsquo;social engineering&amp;rsquo; security: script-kiddies often scan whole IP blocks for a known vulnerability, and only attack those who give back a banner telling that they run the vulnerable service. This howto aims to fake the service banners and in this way, fool the script-kiddies. However, your system will still be vulnerable to an exploit if you&amp;rsquo;re running a vulnerable service! If a script-kiddie runs his exploit, even if he sees you don&amp;rsquo;t send out the right banner, you can still be hacked. So, always keep your system up-to-date, see this as a way to decrease the amount of effective attacks on your system, not as a way to be invulnerable. Of course there&amp;rsquo;s also the fun-factor: it&amp;rsquo;s quite amusing to see script-kiddies attempt to break into your &amp;lsquo;Microsoft-IIS/5.0&amp;rsquo; also known as Apache 1.3.27 &lt;em>grin&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>