<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RFC 2132 on Tech Notebook</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/rfc-2132/</link><description>Recent content in RFC 2132 on Tech Notebook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 20:33:41 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/rfc-2132/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DHCP: Installation and Configuration of a DHCP Server</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/DHCP_:_Installation_et_configuration_d'un_serveur_DHCP/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 22:36:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/DHCP_:_Installation_et_configuration_d'un_serveur_DHCP/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol&lt;/strong> (DHCP) is a network protocol designed to automatically configure TCP/IP parameters for a station, particularly by automatically assigning an IP address and subnet mask. DHCP can also configure the default gateway address, DNS name servers, and NBNS name servers (known as WINS servers on Microsoft networks).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The initial design of Internet Protocol (IP) assumed pre-configuration of each computer connected to the network with the appropriate TCP/IP parameters - this is known as &lt;em>static&lt;/em> addressing. On large or extended networks where changes occur frequently, static addressing creates a heavy maintenance burden and risks of errors. Additionally, assigned addresses cannot be used even when the computer that holds them is not in service. This is a typical problem for Internet Service Providers (ISPs), who generally have more customers than IP addresses available, but never have all customers connected simultaneously.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>