<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Centreon on Tech Notebook</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/centreon/</link><description>Recent content in Centreon on Tech Notebook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 17:45:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/centreon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installation and Configuration of a Centreon Server</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Installation_et_configuration_d'un_serveur_Centreon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 07:37:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Installation_et_configuration_d'un_serveur_Centreon/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Centreon is one of the most flexible and powerful GPL-licensed monitoring software solutions. It&amp;rsquo;s built on top of the OpenSource Nagios technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Designed for a wide range of users, it&amp;rsquo;s perfectly suited for measuring system, network, and application indicators. Centreon brings together essential functions for managing monitoring of critical infrastructures. Being modular, it adapts to your needs and allows you to extend its functionality further.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For my part, I chose to move from Nagios 3 to Centreon to get graphics and reporting capabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oreon: Setting up a simplified and more elegant solution for Nagios</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Oreon_:_Mise_en_place_d%27une_solution_simplifi%C3%A9e_et_plus_%C3%A9l%C3%A9gante_pour_Nagios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 12:43:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Oreon_:_Mise_en_place_d%27une_solution_simplifi%C3%A9e_et_plus_%C3%A9l%C3%A9gante_pour_Nagios/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Oreon is a network monitoring and supervision software based on the most efficient Open Source information retrieval engine: Nagios.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today Oreon no longer exists and is called Centreon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The objective of this project is to provide a new interface for Nagios, capable of giving it new functionalities while keeping the logic of its existing mechanisms. All within a modern, scalable interface designed for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Oreon project benefits from a constantly growing community and unwavering investment, which allows it to make its solution increasingly robust and constantly offer innovative new tools.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>