<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RAM on Tech Notebook</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/ram/</link><description>Recent content in RAM on Tech Notebook</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 17:45:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.deimos.fr/tags/ram/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tmpfs: Mounting a RAM filesystem on Solaris</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Tmpfs_:_monter_un_filesystem_en_RAM_sous_Solaris/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 09:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Tmpfs_:_monter_un_filesystem_en_RAM_sous_Solaris/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>TmpFS (Temporary File System) is the generic name given to any temporary Unix file system. Any file created in such a filesystem disappears when the system is shut down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default implementation of tmpfs in Linux 2.6.x kernels is based on ramfs, which uses the caching mechanism to optimize memory management.
It is also available on Solaris 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, tmpfs additionally offers a memory size limit that is set at mount time and can be modified on-the-fly with the &amp;ldquo;remount&amp;rdquo; option for security purposes. Tmpfs also allows the system to use swap space when necessary, which provides an additional guarantee.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tmpfs: RAM filesystem or how to write to RAM</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Tmpfs_:_un_filesystem_en_ram_ou_comment_%C3%A9crire_en_ram/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 18:47:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/Tmpfs_:_un_filesystem_en_ram_ou_comment_%C3%A9crire_en_ram/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>TmpFS (Temporary File System) is the generic name given to any temporary Unix filesystem. Any file created in such a filesystem disappears when the system shuts down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default implementation of tmpfs in Linux 2.6.x kernels is based on ramfs which uses the caching mechanism to optimize memory management.&lt;br>
It is also available on Solaris 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, for security reasons, tmpfs additionally offers a memory size limit set at mount time that can be changed on-the-fly with the &amp;ldquo;remount&amp;rdquo; option. Tmpfs also allows the system to use swap when necessary, which provides an additional guarantee.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VServer: Setting Up VServer</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/VServer_:_Mise_en_place_de_VServer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 16:43:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/VServer_:_Mise_en_place_de_VServer/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>Linux-VServer is a security context isolator combined with segmented routing, chroot, extended quotas, and other standard tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Initially launched by Jacques Gélinas as the CTX patch, Linux-VServer consists of a patch for the Linux kernel that allows multiple applications to run in different security contexts on the same host machine. Linux-VServer is also equipped with a set of tools to install/manage these contexts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This project allows one or more operating environments (operating systems without the kernel) to run on a distribution, meaning you can run one or more distributions on a single distribution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MFS: Using a RAM Filesystem</title><link>https://wiki.deimos.fr/MFS_:_Utiliser_un_filesystem_en_RAM/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 02:37:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.deimos.fr/MFS_:_Utiliser_un_filesystem_en_RAM/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction &lt;a href="#introduction" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;p>MFS allows you to place a partition in RAM. The advantage is speed. The disadvantage is that you lose all modifications made to it after each reboot. With a simple rsync setup, this can be resolved, which I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configuration">Configuration &lt;a href="#configuration" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>&lt;h3 id="partition-tmp">Partition /tmp &lt;a href="#partition-tmp" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;i class="material-icons align-middle">link&lt;/i>&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>&lt;p>The tmp directory is interesting to move into RAM since the data there is temporary anyway and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be stored on the filesystem. Edit the fstab file:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>